<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: blog | Alex Zeitler]]></title>
  <link href="http://AlexZeitler.com/blog/categories/blog/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://AlexZeitler.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-01-21T23:24:05+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://AlexZeitler.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Alex Zeitler]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hello (from a new) World]]></title>
    <link href="http://AlexZeitler.com/blog/2012/01/12/hello-from-a-new-world/"/>
    <updated>2012-01-12T19:24:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://AlexZeitler.com/blog/2012/01/12/hello-from-a-new-world</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>Yet another blog?</h2>

<p>If you know my blog <a href="http://blog.alexonasp.net">Alex on ASP.NET</a>, you may ask why I started blogging on another Url and a different <a href="http://www.octopress.org">blog engine</a>?</p>

<p>As you may have noticed on <a href="http://twitter.com/AlexZeitler">Twitter</a>, besides ASP.NET MVC and WCF Web API, I started developing mobile-first and single page web applications using HTML5, CSS3 and Javascript a few month ago.</p>

<p>Most of the Javascript and CSS3 frameworks (not least node.js) have their background in the OSS community which is mainly focused on Linux and OS X.</p>

<p>To have that technology stack available just in time (and sadly often long before being available on the Windows stack) for my <a href="http://pdmlab.com">daily work</a>, I decided to step out of the comfort zone / think outside the box (name it whatever you want) and use both platforms on a daily basis also.</p>

<h2>What to expect?</h2>

<p>As I'm pretty new to both OS X and Linux (read: Ubuntu), I'll post about my experiences during my way to the "x world" (not least as a documentation for myself if I forgot about something I already solved).</p>

<p>That means I'll document which languages, tools and frameworks I'll use, what I (dis)like on the "new" platforms etc.</p>

<h2>Will you leave .NET / the Microsoft stack?</h2>

<p>Short answer: No.</p>

<p>Long answer: World is changing fast and a developers (geeks) world even faster and as much as I like ASP.NET MVC and Web API: it's simply on the server side and much things nowadays happen solely on the client (read: client == browser != classic desktop).</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
